Hello; I'm Taran Mangampalli. I'm a
finally a data science student at NRA
Institute of Technology. Today I'm gonna
discuss  these things of two tasks that
is given by Sethaphal as part of
hackathon. So as part of like
evaluation I'm doing this video. So let's
start the video with small
aim and all. So the aim is to build a
toolLike 2 applications where
one works on PDF and other thing works on
websites. Like we need to chat with
websites and PDFs in these two tasks
which are similar quite similar to each
other. The first task is very helpful
for our students where we study different
PDFs for exam purpose.
So it it it helps us to
understand the things and make life
easier. So the other task
also very helpful for us while learning
and building the things we we
like we usually go through different
websites and like get insights from them.
So these two tasks are very helpful for
our student life. So let's start with
quick background like these tasks are
of building a rack chain which is a
retrieval augmented generation. Which
helps us to obtain the concise
information or valuable information
from the LLM's. So
here we use the RAG for building these
applications and by using those
query chain we have done these things of
the two task. So these are the important
and relevance of the project. Advanced
information retrieval as I have discussed
before and real world applications as as
part of student view I have told this one
and we can also consider this for higher
like. of employees and all so
we have used several alums over
here so which is for fostering the
innovations and industry relevance is
nothing but we have I have discussed
before as part of student I have
discussed and another thing is as part of
an employee we can like
integrate these things in our lives and
make life easier so let's start with
a small likeLet me make this
concise and understand for the
like make a short note of this. The first
task was to build a
RAG application where the data will be
processed furtherly and it is stored in
the vector database and we need to handle
the query handling. Another thing is we
need to compare the videos over there and
another thing is like make a response
generation from the user query. So
these are the four like sub task of the
task one and the other thing is chart
with website using rag. This is our task
two where it is similar but the data has
been changed. Here the data will be
of website data. So
let us go through the architecture and
discuss further. So we had used the
Python for for collect.
Scripting and we had used IDE
and Chroma DB as a vector database. I had
gone through the different vector
databases such as Quadrant which I have
used previously in my previous internship
at Invoice Springboard. So for this I'm
going to the Chroma DB because it's quite
uh like the helpful
or these uh land chain because like
had used land chain because it uh similar
is the right. So there the land chain had
has like. Good documentation on
ChromaDB. So I had to choose the ChromaDB
over pattern and I had used the Gemini
AI for emitting. So here I
had searched for Open AI emitting but the
Open AI had stopped it's free
credits. So I had gone through the Gemini
Gemini AI emitting which is free of cost.
So this is the thing and the thing is for
evaluation purpose I had built a small UI
for better understanding and all. So let
us go through the architecture. Now
architecture of task one is nothing but
the user will provide the PDF. The PDF
will be passed to the OCR by using the
OCR module&#44; OCR or my PDF module
and it will be processed by by it's
like OCR&#44; my OCR&#44; my PDF
for module. The each text from the image
can be converted and returned a
OCR PDF file and the OCR PDF
file will be processed. by the
this code like
let me simplify this this is the OCR
like script it will convert the
general PDF to OCR PDF the OCR PDF
will convert the data into chunks and the
chunks will be pushed into the vector
database after that the RAG will be
handling all the things like we build a
chain and the chain will be invoked by
the query soSimilar
way&#44; all multiple PDFs are also
stored in a single data variable and
separated by a backslash N or something
called PDF 1&#44; PDF 2 and all and we
can get the insights from that. And this
is the task 2 which is quite similar to
the task one where the data will be
enter URL&#44; the URL will be
fetched and after that the document
documentation generation where for the
data can be obtained. By using the line
chain or like URL parser&#44; I had used
the URL parser of the line chain
documents. So after that data will be
processed similarly
similar to the task one where it can be
divided into chunks. The chunks can be
divided furtherly into emittings.
Emittings are nothing but PD's numerical
representation where like they
had gone to different databases such as
SQL or like no SQL and this is a vector
database where it is of vectors. We as
we have gone through the like in physics
like vector is something but XYZ in the
similar way it is something called for
numerical representation over there. So
by using the GNI embeddings the
embeddings will be created and it will be
pushed into the vector database. So
furtherly it will be handled by the rag.
We have built a chain of rag and
it will be invoked furtherly by using the
like user query. So this is the
UI for the task one. Here is the UA for
the task one single PDF multiple PDF. It
will be handled based upon the
situation that like we the the
hackathon members have provided 2 tasks
over here. So single PDF will be charting
with single PDF&#44; multiple PDF will be
comparison and all and we can go through
there in our demonstration. But this is
the like UA for the second task
and here we will provide the link
and send the prompt over here.
So let us go to the demonstration purpose
now.
main
it's running so let us handle singlepedia
first so which can be
like one minute give me a minute
let me adjust the camera once
it's fine
so it got it's getting uploaded you can
observe here OCR has been performed over
here and we can write the query
now
like this was the page number okay
Like I had given the prompt to it, it
will go to the right like get the
similarity search and similarity search
will be performed and furtherly it is
handled the LLM which is
running. OK, you can observe here
all the degree percentages have been
obtained over here. So
let me open the PDF over there.
Let me open the PDF.
OK you can observe this thing on the
degree unemployment rate had been passed
over here because we have performed
course here. So we have got these things
and another thing is under like get
these things. So for
better prompting I'm like adjusting the
prompt that had been given in the
evaluation page. So I'm improving the
prompt.
So let me prompt like this tabular
data which is
table
which is
in a proper.
Let me give this query once.
So it does like every time the Gemini
API will be used. So I have integrated
the Gemini API in the dot EME itself.
So the prompt is searching
something and it
will be handled by after that.
So here is the table format.
So individual LLM. But these
values are correct.
You can observe the behavior
here. It's
exact table that had been passed
here. Let me make up that note.
OK, you can observe all the things
having successfully passed.
So let's go to the multiple PDF.
So I'm giving my custom PDF over here.
like let me give this material
and html
and html here
and let me give a short period for
sentimental analysis products release
so let me give these two periods
here you can observe here thisOCR will be
handled on every time. So
what we use
from the
chat set the prompt so it will analyze
and we will be handling as we have
discussed before.
so the query has been sent to the backend
so it is running on the LM
so here
here it is based on the
product this is the
it had given a table that we have these
things are there
okayAnd
we had even different thing, but it like
it has a list and given in the table
format because we have done the table
previously. So it will handle
accordingly. OK,
so let us go through the second task now.
So I'm stopping the server.
OK, let us run this.
So here I need to provide the list
like with a comma. So, let
us go through this website first So, let
us go to the academic panel
here
like we can keep a comma here and change
the comma and set
this
Let's hit enter.
So the data will be passing over these
URLs when the data has been passed. So
we can ask questions like.
Tell me about
the academics.
It's processing.
OK, it's given a short. It had given a
short thing. OK,
let us what does the
website.
describe
ok let's check this one
still processing again let me process
again the website highlights recent news
events and notes in
Washington ok these are the two tasks
they are like they can be they are like
used for this oneOK, like
these are the small areas of files, but
we had gone the main major things.
So let us go to the
code once. So here you
can observe that we had used the
subprocess because we had used
this OCR where subprocess dot
OCR and all these things. I had used the
sub process remaining all the of
document like line chain things and dot
DNV has been used for GMI and has been
used for. So let me divide the thing
single PDF, multiple PDF. So
firstly the like we need to choose the
single PDF and here we had gone through
the single PDF now and. No,
here we had used the chroma dot from
documents which is quite similar to our
quadrant. So firstly it will perform
most here and after that it will load the
PDFs and it will like
perform like chunks over there and the
chunks will be perform like pushing
this chunks into the vector database over
here. So LME's Gen. A as I
had discussed before the like. Here
is the dot ENV file. I had provided the
API key over there and here is a
comparison or something prompt off like
that. So here the user will be giving a
prompt. After that it will be handling
using the rag chain. So let me
like here you can check that chain.
Here is a like we
as I had discussed before it is a QR
chain retrieval action basically.
So here or the chain will be invoked. And
in the input will be processed furtherly.
So in a similar way. OK, so we had gone
through the single one, so let us go
through the multiple one now. So here you
can check that here is the multiple PDF.
Similar thing, but all the docs will be
stored in a list format and the list
format will be uh like. We had
joined these thing and we had gone
through the Chroma DB as similar to the
before one and we have defined a
context over here, context over here and
we have you are an A assistant for
comparison task like that. We had defined
something of like that and so that it
will be handled properly. So here is the
prop and all these thing
like this is defined over here. System
will be this and human will be this
this is like. quite
ohh similar to OpenAI
where we define systemized user.
So here also we had defined by by
using the Gemini. So this is the
thing and similar thing will be performed
now here. Thank you. And next
I need to discuss with
this task to similar thing but.
I had as I had discussed in the
introduction, I had used this
where it is here
first thing over here unstructured URL
loader. I had used this one and I
had passed these URLs and I had obtained
the data and the data will be recursively
turned into chunks and the chunks will be
given to the vector DB and vector DB will
be handling by using the as I have
discussed before it is the like.
similarity search and we have got
the similarity search results and it will
be handled by Chen. So this is the
simple code and
the issues faced by
by building this project is
with OCR and this chroma divi
and so let me show the chroma
divi shown. So here I have
written the codeIn this morning
where I had faced the
issue of from a DB so I need
to clear the. So this is the
issue too and the future
like I can improve this project by
building a OS dot remove by removing
unnecessary files after every these
things and make some
better UI. So
upon the verification purpose I have
done the simple UI. So
these are the issues and improvements
that that can that I can perform in this
task. So thank you. Thank you for giving
this opportunity and I hope
you got a good impression on me.
Thank you. Have a good
day.